Kev Kev Tim, good to see you, man.
>> Dude, glad we're doing this.
>> Yeah. So fun to hang.
>> Back in LA.
>> Back in LA for a little bit. And
it is a nice corner of the world.
>> It's not bad.
>> You know, until the failed state
implodes, it's going to be lovely.
>> Yeah, it's uh we'll enjoy it while we
can.
>> Yeah. So, you have lots that we can talk
about.
>> I've got some things jotted down. Where
should we start? Let's start with
probably the most talked about thing
these days, which is AI.
>> All right.
>> And I, you know, I know people are tired
of hearing about all this AI stuff, but
I think there's been an inflection point
in the last, I'd call it three weeks
>> that I am just really blown away by.
Like AI has turned into something that I
I I kind of saw it coming, but I didn't
think it would come this rapidly,
>> which is it is replacing. So when I
first thought of AI, I thought, okay, we
have this chatbot. We can launch it. We
can ask like questions like of whatever,
you know, I got to repair this light
switch. How do I do it? Like that's
typical AI use case over the last, call
it, you know, two years.
>> In the last call it month, there has
been a release of a handful of AI
assistants that are not your typical
like Chad GBT cla. They're different.
>> So have you played with Instinct at all?
>> I haven't, but I know people are. Yeah.
So you should you should provide some
context for folks who don't let's start
off. So let me first put the these are
the people in the ring that are entering
this new kind of era of personal
assistant AI which is I would say
Instinct Muse which is a a meta product
>> and then you have Grockbot which is
essentially Gro which is Elon's project.
>> So when instinct dropped someone sent me
a text invite was like hey you just got
to sign up for this. I'm like, "Ah man,
I don't want another AI thing." Like,
you know, I I already do this all day
long. I'm using for coding, all that
stuff. Like, whatever. So, the first
thing that you notice is it's not
another app to download.
>> Mhm.
>> It actually is iMessage. So, they have
reverse engineered
>> and they actually give you just a phone
number to chat with.
>> It's closer to WeChat in China. Yeah.
>> In a sense.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Exactly. So, I have this
phone number. I texted it was like,
"Hey, off your Google account." content
like I know this is your nightmare from
a privacy standpoint but it's like you
know give us your Gmail give us your
Google Drive here's a link you just
click here
>> yeah exactly it's like Russian site or
something but I I click through I
authorit I'm like whatever there's some
hype I hear it happening people are
doing this like I don't have any like
nudes but you probably do like I don't
know I don't know how much you keep all
that stuff online
>> probably don't was this
>> your nudes
do you keep it in Google Drive
I just post those to my Tumblr account,
>> your private Tumblr.
>> Yeah.
>> All in all seriousness though, do you
lock down like do you have a separate
offline storage for like sensitive [ __ ]
>> Probably should.
>> Yeah, you should. We should talk about
this off camera. Okay.
>> Like there's just certain things that
like in my mind I'm always like, "Okay,
what's the blast radius of if something
gets hacked?
>> What is
Kevin gives me to worry about?"
>> Yeah. Exactly. Yeah. All right.
>> So, okay. So, you author everything and
the first thing I notice is that this
bot texts me back and it's like, "Hey,
you missed this docu sign from a couple
days ago."
>> And I was like, "Oh [ __ ] well, that was
like kind of helpful, you know?" So, I
went in there and like did it and then
it's proactively just watching
everything
>> and it learns by my responses everything
I've done prior
>> and it really understands what I care
about and what I should pay attention
to.
>> And who manufactures instinct? It's just
a startup. It's a self-named sting
startup.
>> Yeah, it's a it's a startup. It went
from like zero to 10 billion in
valuation in like four months. It's
crazy.
>> Sounds sounds like a sign of the times.
>> Yeah.
>> Now, why would you trust a smaller
company from a privacy and access
perspective
>> versus like Muse from Meta or something?
I trust Muse certainly more because it's
just going to be battle tested.
>> Listen, I I I
scrutiny. I mean, not that they're
always the best actors, but at the same
time, right?
>> Well, they also
>> more maybe more checks and balances.
>> Yeah. And they came out and they they
actually did a whole briefing on their
security model around their private
instance of
>> they
>> a metad with Muse. Yeah. So, Muse is a
very similar product. It actually has an
app. I think they're adding a phone
number and whatnot.
>> And so, it is just it's wild. It's wild
in that this is something where I never
thought it would connect the dots in the
way that it does. is like I'll give you
an example. I was doing an international
flight and I was like, "Okay, I want to
have like a prescription for gabapentin
so I can get some sleep on the flight,
right? Be careful with that." I knew you
have to be careful with it. Like
whatever. So I had a prescription coming
in. It got called in and to get filled
and instinct was like, "Hey, just so you
know, your prescription's ready. You
should go pick it up. Leave by this time
because your flight's on time and if you
want to grab it, go over here now. Grab
it then and then head to your airport."
>> Can I tell you something crazy? Yeah.
just in terms of synchronicity. So 3
months ago, I drafted a preface to the
new book, this book on no that I'm
writing because there are many examples
in the book around assistance and some
of the very early reader feedback
because I tested it with 100 plus people
>> was some of these seem like 1enter
problems. Mhm.
>> And so I wrote a preface which was a
letter from it was called a letter from
the future and it basically talked about
how what's called 78 I was using a gen
one Dexcom which was like sticking
barbecue tines under your
>> I was with you. You got me on to
remember that. The the plunger it was a
plunger for people who don't know this
is a continuous glucose monitor and now
you push a button it's like woo tingly
and you get it in you. You used to have
to stick a plunger into your body.
>> You basically Yeah. you basically had to
stick two very long prongs under your
abdominal skin.
>> Now it's like a little peck on the
cheek. It's so much better. But at the
time I was like, "Nobody's going to use
this." And I was like, "Well, I don't
agree with that because the tech's going
to improve very quickly, right?" And
particularly once it went from this
weird beeper device to smartphone,
it was it was pretty clear that the
adoption was going to be rapid and then
get outside of type 1 diabetics,
certainly type two, but then get to kind
of health healthy normies and worried
well.
>> Yeah.
>> And on the assistance side,
>> I was also pointing out like back in the
day, yes, it was a 1% problem just like
inbox overwhelm and everybody has six
inboxes now. But in the case of
assistants, it's like sure. It went from
like full-time in person to virtual
assistant to digitally enhanced virtual
assistant. And I was like, by the time
you read this, we will have AI
assistants.
>> Yes.
>> That can do 99% of what I'm describing.
And it's already happened. So, I've had
it change flights for me.
>> I've told it there's a restaurant that's
a hard reservation to get into. This is
all instinct.
>> Yeah. I've told it, hey, there's a hard
reservation to get into. and it's like
hey I can't log in with your open table
but it drops at this time every two
weeks it give me a link and it's a
secure like vault and I gave it my table
login and then it nailed it's snag the
reservation for me perfectly and like
add to my calendar and then the cool
thing is if you have multiple friends
with instinct you can friend your
instincts together so I said to a couple
of my friends there was one person I
wanted to take to dinner and our
instincts became friends and so I said
share the calendar invite and all the
details and the instincts talk to each
other and figure out the schedule, pick
up it's magic.
>> This is how Skynet
>> autopop populates for all the
Illuminati. By the way, they don't exist
people. But they put them all in the
same calendar invite to get them into
one spot so the drone swarm can strike
them at once. Yeah, it's going to be
awesome.
>> Uh I'm definitely going to use this.
Everyone is going to be using this,
>> right? I mean, Chatbt just announced
Dots. That's their version of it now. So
that's come out. How do you think about
your
history,
memory, context, right? If you've
predominantly used something, let's just
say this may or may not be true, but if
you've predominantly used chat GPT,
would you be inclined to use dots or
would you be inclined to use something
else? I don't know if they've made it
harder or impossible to export your
>> You can export memories and some of
that, but they are I mean, this is the
wedge that they're looking for. They
want to have something that is uniquely
theirs. That isn't just like what's
happening right now with the AI
enthusiasts is that if there's a new
model that comes out, there's no there's
zero loyalty, right? It's like, "Oh,
Cloud's better. I'll go use Cloud." Oh,
CHTP is better. And like people are
jumping all over the place.
>> This is a finally becoming this durable
storage of your life and your story and
your history and all the things that
you're into. And that is going to be, I
think, something where they're going to
kind of lock that down. the agentic AIS
like once you authorize all that [ __ ]
You don't want to do that every time a
new model drops somewhere else.
>> Yeah.
>> So, question for you. I saw a little
news around this. Somebody a friend of
mine who's keen on startups and
investing texted me about decisions
contrast in styles and business models
between Amazon and Shopify. And this may
have developed very I'm sure it has
developed very rapidly. But I think that
Amazon blocked
Meta's agent.
>> Mhm.
>> Right. In part because Amazon's business
model, I think it's
>> I don't want to hazard a number. It was
texted to me, but
>> they have sponsored placement, they have
advertising. I mean, there are a lot of
drivers that get circumvented, revenue
drivers that get circumvented by Agentic
Commerce, right? So, they blocked it.
And then like 24 hours later, Shopify is
like we are open for business agents
welcome.
>> How do you think that plays out? So this
is actually a you're hitting on a very
fascinating trend which is this idea
where applications destination websites
all those things go away. So in a world
where you say, "Hey, you know, I just
need some new towels for my house,
right? Rather than going on Amazon and
searching for new towels or whatever it
may be or Shopify or whatever
independent shop, you just ask Chad
GBT." Now, what Amazon is worried about
is if they are top of funnel, if Chat
GBT is the entry point, they can just be
swapped out. Yeah. Right. So it's like,
"Oh, you know what? Walmart has the same
thing for $10 less." And they just push
that right into the feed. Mhm.
>> And so for them, they're like, "Oh [ __ ]
this was our moat cuz we were the
destination. Everyone comes to
amazon.com, they shop there, and now the
AI is deciding and buying on their
behalf." So brilliant by Shopify. But
this is happening everywhere. So I'll
give you an example. I just shot a
podcast with uh Henry Shookman, our Zen
Master friend, and I was like, you know,
I don't want to send this over to an
editor. I'm just going to like do it
myself. Yeah.
>> And so Blackmagic, who's a maker of
cameras and editing software, they have
they have great stuff. They have an
editing package called Da Vinci Resolve
and it's like Premiere, Final Cut, any
of these editing software suites that
are out there. Well, what they did is
they launched an M MCP server which
essentially means that with one click
you can tie it to your AI. So, I drop in
three camera shots, two pieces of audio,
and I said, "Go make the podcast." And I
just said that I told that to chat GBT.
It connected directly. I'm watching on
the screen. and it's rearranging
everything, editing it, doing all that
stuff. Same thing happens with Photoshop
now. Same thing happens with CAD
software. You don't need the software
anymore. You just tell the AI. And
essentially, this could be headless.
Like, I would never needed to see
Photoshop ever again. I'm like, "Hey,
just go build me this book or whatever I
want to do or remove this stain or
whatever it is, and it's just done.
>> It's wild because you don't need these
destination sites like an Amazon
anymore. You just talk to your client."
So, in some sense, all these apps are up
for grabs. It's whoever's going to play
nicely with that point of entry, and
that was always Google, right?
>> But the thing about Google, it was
always pushing you to the final
destination.
>> They weren't doing the the e-commerce
themselves. And so, now it's like going
to be all in the one suite. So, you'll
never need to leave Claude or Chap GPT
or whatever. It just does it for you.
It's so crazy.
>> What do you think Amazon does? Because
Amazon I mean does have huge advantages
in terms of economies of scale, pricing,
distribution like physical distribution
of product, speed of delivery, etc.
Right. They still crush as last I
checked. I mean in most cases they crush
everybody else.
>> Yes.
>> But they don't want to take whatever the
hit is for all of these sponsored
placements and everything else.
>> They're going to have to.
>> They're going to have to. So do you
think they launch their own agent if
they already have their own AI? Are they
able to compete? I don't think so
because you have on device. So Apple,
Apple intelligence, those models will
get better. Don't don't count Apple out.
Give them three years, right? And
probably not even that. A year and a
half.
>> That will be that domain. You have
Gemini on Android, which is going to
power all of Android. And then you have
Chat GBT and Anthropic and probably a
couple others that will probably just be
like, "Oh, I don't prefer Coke to
Pepsi." Like you want your own AI. It's
better at certain things. And that will
be the entry point for all of the
internet, all of applications, all of
everything. Sponsor ad revenue on Amazon
goes away largely because it's going to
be sales. Most commerce will start to
funnel. Like we saw this back in the
2000s. So in the 2000s it was like okay
online versus offline commerce, right?
It was like of course everyone goes to
Sears to buy buy their tools, right? And
then all of a sudden oh guess what? 10%
of tools are being sold on you know on
Amazon now or online now. and all of a
sudden, you know, a decade goes by and
you're seeing the vast majority of stuff
that is just being purchased online,
right? Versus that's why Sears and J C
Penney and all these big retailers just
go out of business, right? So, I think
what's going to happen is we're going to
see that transition happen once again,
but it's going to be through the front
ends of AI interfaces. So, you'll just
be talking to your AI like, "Hey, you
know, I just need a refill of this.
Like, can you have it here?" "Yeah, we
got you covered with Walmart. They give
it to you in two hours." Or, "Do you
want to go with Amazon? It's $2 cheaper,
but it'll be here tomorrow." You know,
it'll be those types of real life
conversations that you'll just be having
with your AI agent. It's a wild
transition time.
>> Yeah, I've been watching this, but I've
actually been waiting to have this
conversation. I mean, we'll continue
obviously chatting offline to figure out
>> like where to start, right? If I Well,
maybe you can just tell everybody. So,
it's like if if people are using, let's
just say they're using
>> if they're already using Claude and
>> Claude doesn't have theirs out yet,
though.
>> And Chat GPT.
>> Yeah.
>> All right. And they're like, "Well,
look, if there's an advantage to using
meta, what is it called again?
>> Muse.
>> Muse. If there's an advantage to using
Muse, let me know. Maybe. If there's an
advantage to using Instinct, let me
know. Maybe." How would you experiment?
How would you suggest somebody who is
non-technical experiment with these
things?
>> Well, if you have the chat GPT app on
your phone and you're paying for it,
it's going to be there right now, I
believe, for everyone. Instinct still
invite only, so they're slowly rolling
that out. So you'd have to know somebody
and you can poke around online on
Twitter or whatever and you'll find
somebody.
>> And then Muse has been number one in the
app store for like the last couple of
weeks. So that one's pretty easy to get
and you can just sign up for it. So I
would say probably Muse and Gro is still
behind. Their models aren't the best.
That one I would just like sit on for a
bit. It's a little bit more technical,
but yeah, you can just start right away
and then just play with it because you
you'll launch your little bot and then
it gives you a phone number so you can
actually call your bot. And so like
listen to this. This is actually I'm
calling my agent right now on the phone.
This This is chatbt.
>> Okay.
>> Hi, I'm Sabrina.
>> Hey, good to hear from you.
>> I wanted a sexy voice. I wanted a sexy
voice. Sorry. Can you tell me about the
podcast that I'm shooting today?
>> Sure. Let me pull up what I've got on
that.
You're recording with Tim Ferrris today.
It's 12:30 to 3:30.
>> Probably bleed some of that out.
>> Your social security number is
>> Yeah, exactly. So, but I mean, I can
just call this at any time. It doesn't
cost against your AI credits. So, you
can be in the car and just be like,
"Hey, can you move this for me or you
know, can you follow up with this email
or whatever it may be?" And everything I
need to mess with that it's time for me
to actually
>> It is time. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Step into the arena.
>> Amazing. All right. Call to action. I'm
in. Should we talk about some other
items? Yes. On our non-aggenda, I wanted
to bring back
>> an oldie but goody.
>> I don't know if you've ever tried this.
>> I've not.
>> So, this is a bottle of tablets.
And this is something that I've played
with for at least a decade, probably
more.
>> Few tablets of rectus. This is
this is interesting.
>> It's called beta alanine. And the reason
I started playing with this again, this
is a a dietary supplement is I have I
think you know been getting back into
climbing.
>> Yeah.
>> Rock climbing. And have been training
really seriously for about two months.
So not very long. But I have coaches or
I h I had coaches when I was on the East
Coast and in Austin, but now I'm still
traveling, so that'll get figured out.
But I wanted to see what I could do to
improve endurance because I think like
many people, when you get on the wall,
you're going to use your arms too much.
You're going to end up in these locked
off positions, meaning your arms are
bent
>> and you're going to flame out your
forearms or other parts of your upper
body. So, yes, you need to learn how to
use your feet, and I'm doing all of
that, but I wanted to see if I could
address some of the physical
constraints. And I didn't want to use
some of my normal standards like
creatine because creatine
leads to water retention and weight
gain. And the last thing I need at 180
lbs with these tiny little squirrel
paws,
>> with another limiter being finger
strength, obviously, to add weight. I
didn't want to add weight. it really
adds an additional hurdle to progress.
So beta alanine was something that I
surfaced again and I wanted to see if it
had ever been applied to climbing. And
it turns out that there have been
studies done specifically with elite
climbers and there's not a lot but
randomized and double blinded 15 elite
climbers taking four grams a day for
four weeks or placebo
and somewhat like creatine depending on
which protocol you use. They are large
pills.
This will be fun to watch.
>> Why? Cuz I just Kevin just had two.
What's wrong with
>> I'll I'll explain this not be alien.
>> No, it is. I'll I'll explain some of the
>> some of the side effects in a moment.
That's hilarious.
>> But let me give you the the data first.
And
>> I mean, look, you're
>> I mean, I just thought it was what you
said it was.
>> When you're with Tim, rule number one is
you should never just swallow a bunch of
pills from a bottle that he puts on the
table. But here's the upshot of it. So,
with longer traverse, that means getting
on a wall, moving sideways, right? There
was in the intervention group with beta
alanine after they had kind of
saturated. It takes about two to three
weeks to start seeing results if you're
going to see results. But 57% longer
before falling versus 19% improvement
with placebo
>> and an additional 21 seconds of
improvement beyond placebo.
>> That is a ton. Like it is highly highly
statistically significant. And then
looking at longer traverse and by longer
this means like one to two minutes. So
the duration's really important one to
two minutes
>> which on a say top roping when you have
a rope attached doing like a 35 ft wall
like maybe that's the duration right
which I was doing. I wasn't doing huge
walls like 70 or something like that for
indoor
>> but I was also
>> doing top roping and also bouldering
which is a different thing. So it
doesn't really help super short
bouldering that's without ropes but
doing let's just say 5 to 10 moves to
get to the top campus board like didn't
didn't really help any of that stuff. I
won't bother with defining that but say
longer traverse moves completed right
there's basically like a four move
improvement in the placebo group just
from training effect
>> and then in the beta alanine group it
was 10 moves
>> and I have noticed a difference it took
it took a while and you can't really
separate out all of the elements that go
into it because I am training I'm doing
isometrics
doing
collagen plus vitamin C before training.
So, collagen peptides from Momentous
plus vitamin C, you don't need very
much. 500 milligrams or 1,000
milligrams. Five I think it was as low
as 50 in the research. Boosts collagen
production in the fingers.
>> What's one scoop from them, by the way,
cuz I take the same stuff. What's What's
a full scoop? Do you know?
>> I don't recall what's on the label, but
it's like a scoop of that.
>> It's a few grams.
>> Plus some Yeah. Plus some vitamin C. And
the type of collagen does matter. You
kind of want hide if you can get it as
opposed to bone just to avoid heavy
metal and other contaminant issues. But
the the point being I think this stuff
has really helped to the extent that my
coaches like it was almost by the clock
like when I got to 2 and 1/2 weeks of
taking this not before they were like
whoa what happened there seemed to be
like a phase shift where if I'm working
on
>> and it did for me seem to translate to
bouldering which makes me wonder how
much of it is the beta alanine but
suffice to say I've been very impressed
and this is something where I've done
testing before and after to try to track
some of the improvements. So, it is a
heavy lift though because if I'm taking
in my case not 4 g but 6.4 gram a day
roughly, right? I'm taking eight of
these pills a day, it's a lot. And uh I
would suggest and this gets to the side
effects. This is thorn betalanine SR
that means sustained release to minimize
and I might be getting the pronunciation
wrong on this one side effect which is
called paristhesia. It just means
body tingling basically it feels like
>> it feels like a nasin flush
>> or like
>> many parts of your body fell asleep like
you had crossed your legs for too long
and sat down. What do they attribute
this to? Is this is this a cognitive
thing? Is it ATP? is enhancement like
what was underlying mechanism.
>> I'm actually not sure of it's carnosine
it's I believe it's carnosine saturation
muscular
saturation but I am getting over my skis
so people can look it up but beta
alanine has quite a bit of published
literature on it. I was just very
surprised that there was actually a a
study that got funded for 15 elite
climbers. Like who even pays for that? I
have no idea. Probably some supple Yeah.
some supplement manufacturer probably.
So that is one on the supplements and
since I brought it up in terms of
I I had mentioned with the collagen and
contaminants just a quick public service
announcement if you're taking say
psyllium husks right fiber
>> very helpful for a lot of reasons you
don't just need to be boomers like us
with aging colons and rectums it's also
very helpful for glycemic control like
you can take it for meals and stuff like
that. If you take any kind of fiber, you
do want to add water. But the point is
there are a lot of heavy metals and
contaminants in most common brands of
psyllium husks. So
>> Yerba Prima Y RBA or Organic India are
two that I have looked at testing
results for
>> and those are good. But one doctor joked
to me, he's like, "Yeah, you could go to
fill in the blank major pharmacy chain
and grab something off the shelf, but
it's going to be 2% fiber and 98%
arsenic." It was a joke. It's not quite
that bad, but the contamination actually
is worth paying a lot of attention to,
particularly if it's something like this
that you'd be taking on a daily basis.
>> Yeah. I read another study recently that
just was like, shy, like just killed me.
And that is, you know, those seaweed
chips that you can get at like the
grocery stores, like the little flat
papers.
>> So much microplastics in those cuz
they're pulling all that seaweed out of
the ocean and they're just like
>> filled with microplastics.
>> You just can't win.
>> You can't win. You can't win.
>> Okay, speaking of supplements,
>> you hate creatine.
>> No, I don't hate creatine. I love
creatine. I just don't find it to be the
most helpful for climbing specifically.
>> So, uh, yeah, because it puts a few
pounds of muscle on or whatever. Muscle
water or whatever. It helps me lift more
weight though.
>> Oh, for sure.
>> Yeah. So, creatine, we've talked about
this, I'm sure, at least on I mean,
we've done what, like a couple hundred
random shows. I think we've talked about
this at least 10 of them, which is
creatine can be your friend and
sometimes not so much.
>> Yeah.
>> If you overdo creatine, it is a problem
with the GI. It can be. Yeah. Also, if
you're in airport
>> Oh, god. Yeah. You don't don't do what
Tim does or Well, I don't do it anymore
because I I do learn. I'm slow. But
yeah, if if you're like, "Let me have a
double espresso, some creatine, and MCT
oil on your way to the airport." Don't
do that
>> because disaster pass potential is high.
>> Yeah.
>> I would say also because of some of the
research, you know, Rhonda Patrick has
highlighted on the cognitive benefits.
>> Yeah. 10 grams a day.
>> I was taking 10 grams a day, but I
started getting really wicked muscle
cramps
>> in my hands, my feet, and then I I
dialed it back to five.
>> No cramps.
>> Yeah.
>> So,
>> I'm at five right now.
>> Yeah. I think that for my system at
least and I think Rhonda's also observed
this I might
not be getting that right but I think
she's she's talked about it publicly
also experienced cramping at 10 10 grams
plus per day
>> so I've had all kinds my stomach is
horrible with creatine like I have just
historically
>> you have you're a delicate flower with
the stomach anyway
>> sometimes yeah it depends on the thing
but like sometimes I'm actually really
good it's very confusing but anyway long
story short I was doing some research
and I don't know this brand at all so
take this with a grain of salt, but the
technology is legit. I looked up the
study that the technology they're using
to create a delayed release creatine.
So, this is the only one on the market.
So, if you look at these pills, they
look wild. They have all these little
tiny beads inside of them.
>> And they
>> looks like I think it was Dexatrim back
in the day.
>> Yeah, totally. Yeah. But I will tell you
like this is the first one I've been
able to take because of the delayed
release and it does not mess up my
stomach at all. It's amazing. Well,
yeah, you're burying the lead here. Body
Techch Elite Dean Beadllet.
>> Oh, okay. Here's here's the I think
critical piece
>> with Nova Spheres trademark.
>> Yeah. So, I did the research on what
Novars are and they're legitimology.
>> Yeah.
>> All right. Look at that.
>> Yeah. So, I mean, if if it's just one of
those things where like, listen, I I
have also when I travel, I'll use I I
kind of flip brands all over the place,
but lately I like the stuff from
Momentous because of the quality checks
they do.
>> And I have their little travel satchels
that I take with me and just mix them
with some stuff. As long as I slow drink
it over like 3 hours, I'm fine, you
know? But this is the first time I've
been like, "Okay, on the go, I can just
like chug five pills at once and no
issues." So, anyway, that one's fun.
>> Should we talk about sperm quality?
>> Let's do it. Oh, that's where I wanted
to go next. How did you know? God, we
>> I got the request.
>> Yeah,
>> Kevin tried to anonymize it
>> through through random YouTube live
stream and I was like, please talk about
sperm quality. I was like, all right, I
know it's you, Kev. Kev,
>> was this a question somebody wrote in?
>> No, I'm kidding.
>> For yourself?
>> So, I have long been fascinated with
nuts. Not in the testicle sense,
although that's probably true. Also,
just some of the benefits of consuming
different types of nuts like Brazil
nuts.
>> Jesus.
>> I literally thought you were talking
about a ball sack the entire time you
were saying that.
>> There is a double antandra here.
>> So, I talked about for instance Brazil
nuts and selenium way back in the day.
And of course, you have to look at the
funding sources and so on, but
>> there's a brand of nut butters. I'm sure
they do other things called Artisana.
And I don't know why their their raw
almond butter is just better than every
other brand in terms of consistency.
They somehow homogenize that might not
be the right word, the oil so that
you're not dealing with like the oil
slick on the top and like getting it all
over your countertops and stuff,
>> but I ended up just for shits and
giggles buying their walnut butter cuz I
had never had walnut butter and it has
some cashews in it. Mhm. And
you know, I'd like to have a family,
ideally a couple of kids. So, it's good
as as as I age into my soon 50s, I'm
like, you know, I should keep the twins
>> as healthy as possible. And I tend to
think that if you optimize for
fertility, you get a lot of other things
right
>> as downstream effects.
>> And the two ingredients are raw walnuts
and raw cashews. I'm bringing this up
because
there are actually walnut specific
studies. There was a 2012 randomized
control trial in 117 healthy men aged 21
to 35. And they were randomized to
either continue their normal diet or add
75 grams a day of walnuts. And it's not
impossible. Like 75 grams just to turn
that into something people might
recognize. It's like 6 cups of chopped
walnuts. Like two and a half handfuls.
It's not that crazy. Yeah.
>> And the improvements in sperm vitality,
motility, and morphology all were
statistically significant.
>> Wow.
>> Yeah.
>> We just want Are there other health?
>> That's the question. That's the
question. So, generally speaking, nuts
seem to be supportive of fertility. So,
in 2024, there was a meta analysis that
showed that at least 60 grams per day,
so that's less than the 75 we talked
about. Let's call that two handfuls of
nuts as an estimate. Improved sperm mo
sperm motility, vitality, and
morphology. Although it did not
significantly improve sperm
concentration. So,
>> of course, be aware of the caloric
density, right? If you're just housing
nuts all day, you'll have 6,000 calories
of nuts, it's going to have other side
effects. But I thought this was super
fascinating and it only came about
because I ended up loving this walnut
butter and I was like
>> I have read or actually not read. I had
been told that wal consuming walnuts
could improve testosterone and free
testosterone and I was like let me fact
check that. And I did not get back
confirmation on that but I got back
these research results related to sperm
quality. I was like fantastic. Okay.
Yeah, with Brazil nuts in the selenium
side of things, it was a reduction in
prostate cancer, right? There was some
study that
>> I don't I don't recall. For me, the
reason that I was looking at that with
for our body and man, it's crazy to
think about how [ __ ] hard
factchecking and research was back then
compared to now.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Oh my god, it's like you kids have good
now
GPT and Claude and so on. It's so much
easier. You need to know how to
interrogate the system. But the reason I
was looking at that and this is still
relevant today that that looking at your
micronutrient
consumption and absorption matters right
so if you have a copper deficiency or a
selenium deficiency that can be
reflected in all sorts of issues with
say sex hormones
>> right and I have friends there's one
actually multiple friends who had
testosterone issues is they ended up and
I don't know who the latest and greatest
I think it was Spectraell back in the
day but I don't know who the latest and
greatest would be for options for
testing but they ended up just having
like three
Brazil nuts a day and they're like I
feel like I'm on cocaine like their
lived experience
>> changed so dramatically and sure this
isn't randomized controlled I don't know
if that was placebo or not but I saw it
enough times where I'm like look this
seems to be low hanging fruit.
>> Yeah.
>> Top soil is depleted everywhere. You can
be sure as [ __ ] that most
>> vegetable matter you're consuming is not
as nutrient-dense as you would like
probably.
>> So, it's just something to keep an eye
on.
>> Yeah. And so, people should also know
that Brazil nuts, like that nut, it it
receives its selenium from the soil
itself. So, it's the uptake from the
soil. I've seen this now at grocery
stores. There's Brazil nuts that aren't
even made in Brazil.
>> Yeah. So you have to make sure like it
has to say product of Brazil on the back
of the nuts. Is there a certain brand
that you like when it comes to that or
are you just checking for that on the
label?
>> I'm looking at not really. I mean I
haven't done the due diligence there.
I've just been looking for organic cuz
man oh man like I really want to
minimize pesticide consumption. I
understand there are issues with the
designation of organic to begin with.
But it I mean this is just a general
kind of meta principle that or it
underscores a meta principle that I
think about a lot which is like you're
there's the expression you are what you
eat but that's not sufficient like you
are what you eat ate right so if you're
eating salmon like not all salmon is
created equal like what is the salmon
consuming
>> right
>> right similarly this applies to
>> vegetables It applies to salad greens
like where was this grown? How was it
grown? What were the nutrients
>> that were absorbed or not absorbed that
were present or absent?
>> And uh with tools that you have now, I
mean it's a lot easier to try to do this
type of due diligence.
>> Yeah.
>> Most people don't know that non wild
salmon like they add dyes to like make
them it look more pink, which is just
insane.
>> Yeah. There's a lot of this kind of
stuff. And look, I mean, you don't have
to get every detail right, but there are
little things here and there to pay
attention to. And you there are also
like lots of weasel words out there when
people say all natural, right? I mean,
there are many terms that are just not
defined in any meaningful way. So, they
can be used to confuse consumers. But
look,
>> point of the story is
>> walnuts perhaps good for your nuts.
>> I'm going to do it. So, and Artisana
products are delicious. So, why not try
them out? Should we just keep going on
the food?
>> The food kit. I have so many supplements
and [ __ ] today. This supplement day. So,
this actually I've been doing more gym
time, which has been great. Been trying
to like, you know, get a little lean,
try to lift a little bit more weight.
I've been trying to find like a good
source I brought you this one. Oh,
thanks.
>> A good source of protein. Can
>> I try it?
>> Yeah. So, I have no By the way, none of
the stuff we talked about today. No, we
have no affiliation with this stuff. So,
this was one that I found largely
because A2 protein, are you familiar
with A2 at all?
>> So, I I am I have not done my own
homework on this, but I can tell you how
I I came across this just so people
understand what we're talking about. You
want to read the label here because you
sent me a hilarious video of your
refrigerator where you're like, I got a
little bit of this, a little bit of
this, and then we have some protein. And
there were like 40 of these in your
refrigerator.
>> Well, I mean, Pioneer Pastures.
>> Yeah. So this is Pioneer Pastures. I
mean they literally sell it at Target
and whatnot. A2 protein though was the
only protein that cows would produce
about a thousand or so years ago. They
said 500,000 years ago somewhere around
there until this variant took over and
it was became non A2 and it became a
combination of A1 and A2. And it's it's
a type of protein that comes from the
casein which is the slower digestion
version of protein.
>> Bodybuilders used to take casing at
night before they would go to bed
because of the cottage cheese.
>> Yeah. Exactly. So, but the thing about
A2 and what's so cool about it is that
way less stomach discomfort. Like, it is
the natural clean form of protein and
it's really hard to find. So, I found
this one drink, 160 calories, 30 gram of
protein. It doesn't need to be
refrigerated until you lactose
>> free. Lactoseree
>> and it tastes really good.
>> Yeah, it's pretty good.
>> Um, it was two grams of sugar. I mean,
>> I enjoy it. So, for me, this is like a
great I just want something first thing
in the morning to kind of like
especially if I train hard the day
before, like to just get some protein in
the body, take this with some coffee.
It's fantastic.
>> You know, the first time I saw this,
this is the first time I've tried it,
actually, but first time I saw this was
in the offices of Chris Williamson, the
podcaster. No way. He is jacked AF. I
mean, the guy is basically a
bodybuilder. I mean, he's very strong,
very lean. And much like your
refrigerator, there were like 30 of
these sitting in a in a fridge at the
offices.
>> And that was the first time that I had
someone describe to me the
difference, I suppose, or the the
differentiator with AE2 protein.
>> It doesn't taste bad, right? I mean,
>> no, it's totally fine.
>> There's a lot of shitty tasting protein
out there, so I was pleasantly pleased.
>> There's also a lot of protein products
that are basically candy bars or junk
food masquerading as health food. So,
looking for kind of the minimum
effective dose of ingredients.
>> Yeah. I mean, this has monk fruit in it,
but it doesn't have any of the other
like fake sweeteners or anything. And
it's
>> very, very few ingredients relative to
like if you were to compare, not to
throw them under the bus, cuz I will
occasionally have them when I'm caught
in a pinch, but like if you were to
compare the number of ingredients on
this Pioneer Pastures with say muscle
milk.
>> Yeah.
>> It's like seven ingredients versus 40.
Dude, muscle milk was like the like gym
shake during like the 90s, right? Like
everybody wanted muscle milk.
>> Yeah. Yeah. You know, hey, desperate
times. What was that pre-workout that
everyone took that just got you cranked
as [ __ ] in explode?
>> Oh god, that stuff. Yeah. I mean,
basically just bodybuilder crack. It was
so strong. So I I you know on the muscle
milk I you might find this interesting
like
when I was training to compete this is
probably two years ago in
archery. So I had like my period of
intense training and the reason I'm not
doing as much of it anymore is because
it's just very isolating right like
you're it is a solo practice and you're
repeating the same thing over and over
and over and over again. I do still love
it, but I wanted to do something more
social. Yeah.
>> And just a little more physically
engaging like rock climbing,
>> right?
>> Which I I just love to no end every
aspect of it.
>> So fun.
>> The reason that Muscle Milk is relevant
to this story is that I wanted
training nutrition that could not be
broken by inconvenience on the road. So
basically when I was doing my training
sessions, which would be like 3 to four
hours, and this is going to sound gross,
but basically I would only consume stuff
that I knew I could get at almost any
any gas station because I knew my
competition was going to be in
Lancaster, Pennsylvania. And Lancaster
is actually a beautiful town, but I
didn't know where the competition would
be. And I suspected it would be in the
middle of nowhere, and I would only have
access to gas stations or some type of
quick convenience store like a 7-Eleven.
And that turned out to be the case. But
I was comfortable with muscle milk,
almonds, like roasted almonds of some
type
>> and
then zerocalorie monster energy.
>> Oh god,
>> I know. I know. With some torine, right?
But I got comfortable
using the most commonly available stuff
so that I felt like I had and even if
it's only psychological, a competitive
advantage. Oh, an unsweetened
iced tea. That's it. And in any case,
that was my sidebar note on muscle milk.
>> You look at the ingredients now. I don't
know if it's changed, but back in the
day, it it was not healthy stuff.
>> Yeah. And it's like, look, I mean,
>> great name though.
>> Great name. Also,
as I continue to do intermittent fasting
a few times a week, I don't do it a ton
because I'm actually trying to I want to
add some like muscle mass and connective
tissue strength, and you just need
nutrition for that. Did you get that
gripper, by the way?
>> Yeah. Look, I have grippers.
>> Did you get the one that our buddy sent
us?
>> No, I got a different adjustable gripper
because my right arm is still recovering
from the elbow surgery I had a year ago.
>> We should link that up in the show
notes. That gripper that that's a really
good one.
Yeah. Yeah. We'll we'll link to a couple
of different grippers if people are
interested. I I'm going pretty light cuz
I'm still strengthening the extensors
and the right elbow that was repaired.
>> But you want to hear about something
crazy?
>> Yeah.
>> That I've been getting really into. And
this is this is going to get into crazy
town, but you know, we like getting into
crazy town a little bit. So, uh, dream
engineering and anesthesia dreams. So
I've been going down this rabbit hole
related to dream engineering. So can you
modify dream content? Can you for
instance facilitate two-way
communication between scientists and
dreamers while they are dreaming?
>> And this this is a longstanding interest
of mine. And I first read Exploring the
World of Lucid Dreaming by someone named
Steven Labberge the very very beginning
of high school and became very
interested in lucid dreaming which is
just to define terms
>> where you train yourself and there is a
process for this to induce lucidity
while you're dreaming. That just means
you become conscious of the fact that
you are dreaming. And with exercises,
you can get to the point where you're
able to modify your own dream content.
>> And I used to, for instance, in high
school when I was competing in
wrestling, I would do additional
training sessions at night in my dreams.
I'm not making this up. And I felt like
there was a direct translation to
improve performance. Okay. But flash
forward, I connected I ended up getting
inter introduced to uh Dr. Adam Harowitz
who took research out of MIT and Harvard
to make dream engineering a reality. So
he has a startup called Dust Dust S. And
in full disclosure, I I am an investor
in that. But
>> what does it do? They're going to be
helping people to modify dream content
to address things like PTSD.
>> Oh, no way.
>> Now, that's where the conversation
started. And he knows that I have
long-standing interest in psychedelic
related therapies. But psychedelics have
taken a backseat for me in the last
handful of years because most people I
shouldn't say most many people will not
be able to take psychedelics for whether
it's health reasons contraindications
they have psychiatric conditions like
schizophrenia in their family that mean
it would be ill advised to take them.
>> So I've been really focused as you know
on neurom modulation brain stimulation
and I still am super super bullish.
>> How often are you doing that now? Uh I'm
going to be doing it again probably in
the next month. I would say every 3 to
four months.
>> The update there I did get involved with
one company
and I thought very heavily about it
called Ampa Health AM PA Health. They
have the smallest most modular option on
the market.
Very easy to use and I think they are
the company if I had to bet on one
that's going to get to the point where
you can actually power something off of
an iPhone.
And they're doing some really really
interesting work work. Just to touch on
that, they're doing one day protocols
now. So instead of five days off of
work,
>> that's amazing.
>> Costs 30 grand or something, you're
doing one day of treatment accelerated
with this
very small dose of antibiotic called
descloer, which induces plasticity in
the brain, much like certain
psychedelics. So you basically let that
dissolve in your mouth beforehand. And
from let's say a 1 to 10 in severity,
let's say my OCD, generalized anxiety,
it's at like a eight or a nine. It has
taken it to like a a zero or a one.
>> Holy [ __ ]
>> One day. Now it gets crazier though
because you can also use it. People can
check out AMP Health.
>> Do they do it in LA as well or no?
>> They're all they're all over the
country. I mean I mean what I what I'm
hoping is that people who are already
administering things like ketamine or
>> who are offering CBT or whatever will
will just offer this as an add-on
because most of the devices that are
available now are like the size of a
refrigerator. You have to sign like a4
million dollar lease. The Ampa Health
product for providers is like three
grand a month. You can cancel any time.
>> I think that's still accurate and it can
fit in like the trunk of a car. It's
much easier to use.
>> But what's also amazing,
>> and I did this recently when I was
traveling, met a technician and did like
2 hours of I think it was steims every
30 minutes just for a handful of minutes
each simulation.
>> Sims simulations. Okay.
>> Just for sleep,
>> different target area of the brain. Then
>> in this case, it was the same target.
that they're not talking about super
publicly yet,
>> but very easy for therapist like
technicians to find. How do they find
it? Are they just like measuring your
head and [ __ ] and looking like it's all
based on really, really good science.
They're looking at over overlapping
networks that are identified by looking
at data from deep brain stimulation,
data from lesion research.
>> No, but I mean when they sit down with
you, like if you're going to go into
this place and they're like, "Hey, I got
to find this region in your brain. Part
of what makes how they do it interesting
is they're finding targets that are more
uniform person to person.
>> So certain places like the dorsalateral
prefrontal cortex, certain areas on the
front of the skull or front of the
brain, front of the head, right,
>> are a little more variable. You have to
be very precise. So they're finding ways
to make it
very effective, very fast, and less
likely
to suffer from like clinch and error,
right? Because if you really have to
thread the needle,
>> sometimes you get no effect. That
happened to me when I was using like
earlier targets with other hardware.
>> If they were off by like a half a
centimeter,
>> nothing. And you just wasted a week,
right? And like 30 g. No downside. Like,
are you not getting headaches afterwards
or anything weird?
>> Mild headache. Mild headache for like a
day. Does that not freak you out,
though? I mean, that's the only reason I
haven't tried any of this stuff. I'm
like, I don't know. Like, it's like
they're just put magnets in your brain
and [ __ ]
>> I mean, I mean, just to bust your balls.
Before we started recording, you were
talking about some drugs you were
experimenting with.
>> Yeah, but it's like just that's a good
old time. It's
>> Yeah, I tried and true.
>> Yeah.
>> You've done it, too. I mean, look. Okay.
I'm no stranger to farm.
>> I love that. You're going to say it
online.
>> No, I'm no stranger to pharmarmacology.
I'm just saying in this particular case,
I personally found the I think the risk
benefit ratio is much more attractive
for the general population than
psychedelics, which is why I'm spending
so much time looking at it.
>> I think it is much much much more
attractive. M
>> it's faster and frankly
>> well let me let me let me come back to
these these crazy stories of dream
engineering and anesthesia dreams
>> so from uh you know the startup dust
right and people can check out the ampa
health I encourage them to check it out
>> but they're all over the country now and
>> is that the publicly traded company one
or
>> no it's okay private
>> so dust does the dream engineering and
then he introduced me to some research
out of Stanford Here are some of the
headlines of pieces published by
Stanford Medicine. Could anesthesia
induced dreams wipe away trauma? Another
one. Could anesthesia dreams be a more
palatable psychedelic therapy? All
right. So, what does this actually mean?
Let me read some of this stuff. Uh, all
right. What What dreams here? Here's
here's the dream protocol.
>> Yeah, that's what I want to know. What's
the protocol?
>> I tried to convince I was getting an
endoscopy recently just to look at my
throat. You know, you you got to do that
stuff. the endoscopies, colonoscopies
and so on. And I was trying to convince
this doctor I'd never met to do this for
me. And he was like, "Yeah, I don't
think so." But the dreaming protocol has
five steps. Number one, tell the patient
they might dream under anesthesia.
Number two, use propall. Right.
>> Oh, this is great.
>> Uh, yeah, very common.
>> What Michael Jackson did.
>> Michael Jackson used that plus like six
other things.
>> U,
>> I have a great story about that.
>> You should not DIY propall but using
propall as an anesthetic as the patient
is emerging from anesthesia. So, here's
the thing. If someone has surgery,
they're not changing the anesthesia
delivered for the surgery. They're
basically using propall to taper them
out
>> and tune them to a very particular dose
and let's call it radio station so they
have pleasant dreams. Okay. But step
number three is monitor brain activity
etc with EEG.
>> Ensure at least 10 minutes of quiet
undisturbed emergence. This is really
important. If you don't do that then
dream recall is shot. And then you have
to ask them about dream recall. But the
the point of this is that the what
they're seeing and this is not this is
not really super speculative. I mean it
is at the edges now but uh they are
seeing people with longstanding complex
PTSD. They have one of these dreams
where they taper out on propall and they
rehearse beforehand to basically imagine
their traumatic event ending in a better
way with some kind of resolution.
>> And some of these people 10 months later
still zero symptoms of complex PTSD.
They go from severe to zero. The reason
I find this so interesting and other
people find it interesting is that it
underscores the possibility that and
I've thought this for a very long time
but like the trip matters right because
in the world of psychedelic medicine and
business right now
>> the name of the game
>> if you want to ramp up your market cap
and have an exit for $2 billion or
whatever or launch something with an you
know an IPO and make tons of money is
you say, "Okay, psychedelics,
broadly speaking, a whole lot of them
hit these serotonin type 2A receptors.
Let's create a drug that hits the same
receptors, but that doesn't cause the
trip because the trip doesn't matter.
The trip is a side effect, right?
>> Sounds [ __ ] but yeah."
>> Well, what's interesting is that I think
it's both. But just to just to be clear
like you can hit the serotonin type 2A
receptor with no trip like an LSD
variant and it can be very effective for
things like cluster headaches.
>> Sure.
>> It does something.
>> Yeah. But I'm talking about the
emotional release that comes from
>> Sure. But but but so I would say like
also some of these psychedelics and not
all of them are primarily hitting the
type 2A receptor but have potent
anti-inflammatory effects right at
subperceptual doses. So also I think
that could lead to anti-depression and
stuff right.
>> Um however if dream engineering like
Allah dust right if dream if they can
dream engineer people
>> to have fewer nightmares which they can
and that has psychedelic like outcomes.
It's like is it possible that even
though there are millions of people for
whom psychedelics will never be
appropriate like tripping balls for 4 to
6 hours
>> and there are shorter acting
psychedelics and so on, methylone and so
on. I get it.
>> But there are plenty of people who will
never be able to take take psychedelics.
>> Is it possible that every night you have
an opportunity to harness something
similar? And if so, like who are the
scientists who are going to figure out
how to mold that and shape it? And so
what is do the prep work? I I I think
it's all touching the same stuff. Let me
ask you a question. What does Dust do?
Is it a coaching service? Like because I
I have this app that, by the way, I I
have no affiliation with this, but I I
you should check this out too, Tim. I
think you'd really like it.
>> Before I go to bed, there's an app I use
called Claria. C L A R I A. And it is
the best hypnosis app that I found out
there for a variety.
>> Who makes Claria? I may have I may have
tried. you would recognize the
scientists and the team behind it. It's
amazing. It's expensive. It's 150 a
year, so it's not cheap, but I found it
to be a beautiful way to drift off to
sleep, and I swear I feel better the
next day. And there's a variety of
different topics. It can be anxiety. It
can be whatever. But anyway, my point is
my question about dust is okay,
>> what is the thing? Is it is it could you
sit there in this propall kind of state
coming out?
>> So, just to be clear, dust isn't doing
anything with propall.
>> That's totally okay. So, could you do
this with hypnotherapy?
>> That's a great question. I don't know
the answer. I also just to be on the
safe side, I don't know what they're
disclosing publicly, so people can check
out the website and whatever it says it
says.
>> But it's something I'm keeping an eye
on. But broadly speaking, that ended up
being the wedge in the door for me to
get back into doing a deep dive on
>> basically dream shaping,
>> right, which is 100% possible.
>> Mhm. And it's already been demonstrated
that you can have dreamers who achieve
lucidity communicate with researchers
while they are provably in an RAM state
by memorizing eye movement patterns in
advance like Morse code basically like
right left right left something like
that to indicate like I know that I'm
dreaming and I'm telling you I'm
dreaming. It's [ __ ] crazy.
>> And uh have you talked to Matt Walker
about this? I haven't I haven't had a
chance to talk to Matt about this stuff
yet.
>> Yeah. So, Matt used to run the for
people who don't know, you run the you
wrote the why we sleep book and also
used to run the Berkeley Sleep Lab uh
for a long time. So,
>> yeah. Yeah. He's still very active.
>> He's in Dallas now. Has a huge lab is
doing lots of good work.
>> Um he and I on the sleep front have
mostly talked about the Dora class of
drugs.
>> Yes.
>> And just with the You
>> still have a ton of that by the way.
>> Oh yeah. I'm using something called
Qivic instead of Bell Sombra now. Yeah.
But and talk to your doctor, guys. This
is this is not stuff
>> you can't get it without the doctor
anyway.
>> Yeah. I mean, who knows, though, if
they're buying stuff online from Mexico
or whatever. Just don't screw around
with any of this stuff without talking
to your doctor. But the the point of
that for people who maybe haven't
>> heard anything about this, Matt Walker
has a good podcast episode on this. It's
probably 6 to9 months old at this point
about the Dora, like Dora the Explorer,
D O R A class of drugs. That's dual
ereexen receptor antagonist drugs.
There's some evidence to suggest it
might be helpful for people
with family histories of Alzheimer's and
things like that for
>> they do a spinal tap and saw that
>> beta beta amaloid clearance or health
amala clearance.
>> Yeah. Yeah. They they not just in
animals but they've looked at human
data. Well, for me, honestly, even
though it might be a speculative at this
point, because no one's proven that it
prevents Alzheimer's,
>> I'm like, you know what, that [ __ ] is so
scary and I've seen relatives just
disintegrate. I'm like, eh, since I'm
APOE34, I'm genetically predisposed.
>> Let me just be on the safe side.
>> Yeah, I I bring it with me. I'm actually
going to Japan soon. And that's when I
use it. I'm like, I I'd rather do that
than some type of like, you know,
>> these other class of sleep drugs have
been shown to do all kinds of horrible
things, including cancers and you name
it. So, these are the
>> they look like on paper so far to be the
safer class of drugs.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. I mean, there's some other drugs
that seem not to affect sleep
architecture horribly, like, you know,
the ambience of the world like Trazadone
might be a decent choice, but
>> for a host of reasons, I wanted to just
it it just seemed to make sense to me to
look at the the Doras All right. What
else you got? Okay, I'm going to do
rapid fire. I got to get a few things.
First of all, have you ever seen these
before?
>> Plum flour curing pills.
>> Yes. Plumflower curing pills, my
friends.
>> No, I
>> economy size.
>> Okay, hold on. Hold on. Hold on. Oh,
this gets better.
>> I had a buddy.
>> Yeah.
>> He's like, Kevin, you don't understand.
I was actually in in in Paris and I had
like a little bit of like a stomach
like, "Oh man, my stomach's a little bit
off." Like blah blah. And he goes, "I
was about to get food poisoning. I felt
it coming on." Yeah. I had had I think
it was oysters or something he had. He
goes like, "I took two of these. It's
from a Chinese practitioner." And he
goes, "I dodged a bullet every time."
And let's just call it like once every
eight weeks where you're like, "Ooh, my
stomach's a little sideways." You know,
>> I take one of these little packets
>> and it freaking works. And I dude, I'm
telling you, I know it sounds crazy. And
so before the podcast,
>> you just laced with tons of antibiotics.
>> Yeah, exactly. No, I before the podcast
I was like I wanted to look it up cuz
it's like a traditional Chinese medicine
and I can't pronounce any of the [ __ ] in
it. It's a bunch of wild It's like 15
different Chinese herbs.
>> Yeah, this is unlike the A2 protein.
This has like 27 different ingredients
in size two font.
>> I'm telling you, these little packets
are like 50 cents a piece on Amazon.
>> You can buy them in a smaller thing.
>> I just love that they're called curing
pills.
>> They work, dude. I if you at all like
you know what they work with really is
like if you had too much to eat and
you're like oh I'm bloated like I just
feel bloated like just take one little
package take up with ready to go%
owner in the company
>> I'm like well that executive chairman
Kevin Rose what is this
>> my pictures on the outside you get to
Shanghai
>> this thing a rapid fire a fit
>> oh I've got one of those in my bag in
your pack what the [ __ ]
>> like on you right now?
>> Well I don't have it right now but it's
in my backpack. So tell people about it.
>> But the uh I was not able to get the app
to work for
>> I got working.
>> You did? Was it a pain in the balls?
>> It was a little bit of a pain. So you
can get the one without the smart
technology in it, but this will also
work if you don't even use the app.
>> Yeah.
>> So So for people that don't know this
device right here,
>> I should just use it without the app
because it's been basically I downloaded
the app and then they're like, "Oh, you
want any utility out of this app at all?
Pay $79 a month or whatever." And I was
like,
>> there's no you can just ask Catch Beauty
for a training protocol. Yeah.
>> So, there's two knobs on here on each
side of this thing that adjust the
resistance on inhale and exhale. So, you
put this thing in your mouth like this.
This is to train your respiratory
muscles.
>> Yeah.
>> So, that's difficult for me to do.
>> They showed after 8 weeks a 30% increase
in lung capacity when you train with
this thing, which is just insane.
>> The respiratory muscle training devices
are really cool. I had Boss Ruten, this
UFC, but also prior to that, like in
Japan, MMA legend on and he's done this
stuff basically daily for multiple
years. There's good data to to suggest
reductions in lower back pain, all of
these different issues if you improve
the strengthening of the muscles that
aid in respiration.
>> Wow. Do you have the same model? Like
the same type?
>> I have a white one that's got like
Bluetooth and all this fancy technology
that I think I do not need. When did you
buy it?
>> I bought it probably a year ago.
>> Okay. I don't know why this had the
latest firmware on it and it works fine.
I haven't had any issues with the
connectivity, but I did have one before
my house burned down and it it was
always having issues connecting. So, I
don't know.
>> All right. Maybe I need a new one. But
Airfitit, please improve your app if you
haven't in the last year because I found
it to be incredibly difficult.
>> Uh, plus your base baseline of
programming for somebody who's bought a
device should be decent. Yeah. But I do
have I do have one in my bag at home.
So, I will I will I will just use chat
GPT or Claude to help me figure out a
>> Bluetooth free option for training.
>> You can also um what I've been doing
with it is Ruck backpack 6% incline on
the treadmill.
>> That sounds comfortable
>> with this in my mouth and it's really
helped.
>> I'm guessing the people on the
treadmills next to you just clear out,
huh?
>> No, I might. It's at my house, but yeah,
>> I'm not doing this in public. It's
ridiculous. Okay, the last one I have is
about man makeup, but we can get to
that.
>> Let's come back to man makeup. I'll give
another bit of science that I think is
pretty fascinating to watch. This was
sent to me by an oncologist who
specializes in
on one level cancers around the eye. So,
I had a scare. I might have told you
about this. I'm not sure. Still a little
bit of a scare, but there was a neas
found at the back of my eye, which is
like a large freckle, and that can
develop into cancer.
>> Oh [ __ ] The good news is they can get
rid of it. The bad news is you lose your
eye. So,
>> right,
>> this is something I've tracked first
every 3 months, then every six months.
It hasn't changed in size,
>> but really uh came to admire.
>> Where did you find this by the way?
get your eye exam but with retinal
scanning with like ver with advanced
imaging and certainly I was happy to
find it but I mean very scary to find
those moment because you don't know if
it's been there for 20 years or if it's
been there for a month and a half.
>> This is my brain aneurysm.
>> I had a little tiny brain aneurysm that
was like you know 1 millimeter whatever.
>> So you found out with like biograph or
something?
I did and they're like, "Okay, well, we
have to watch this and it could explode
if it gets too big." And then after 2
years, they're like, "Oh, you probably
just have this since you were born." And
I'm like, "Ah, shit." Okay.
>> So, she has occasionally will send me
science that she finds interesting. And
this one, I mean, this is this is
probably not the description of the
study itself. I think I went to the lay
person's interpretation of it, but the
the headline here, which I put in my
newsletter, five bullet, check it out.
tim.blog/fr.
Brain stimulating contact lenses match
Prozac and depression study. All right,
so this isn't an animal model, but let
me read the synopsis. Material
scientists have developed a wearable
drug-free contact lens capable of
treating depression by delivering mild
electrical signals through the retina.
>> Wow. The study demonstrates that these
specialized lenses are as effective as
flockitine, that's the active ingredient
prozac, at reducing behavioral, neural,
and and physiological signs of
depression in mice. Okay, so mice are
not just little furry humans. So just
keep that in mind. This technology
leverages the eyes anatomical connection
to the brain to stimulate mood
regulating circuits non-invasively. So
that is pretty fascinating, right?
Imagine if now I don't know
mechanistically what it's actually doing
with the stimulation.
Is it affecting veagal tone? Is it
affecting something else? Who knows? I
haven't done the deep dive on it yet.
But imagine this is where bioelectric
medicine, right? Whether it's different
types of stimulation for increasing
bagel tone.
>> There are a lot of [ __ ] devices out
there, folks. So just be aware. I'm not
aware of anyone commercially available
that is not prescription that is
credible. But
you talked like Michael Lean of Tufts,
like will we more and more be able to
use electricity instead of pills?
>> Mhm. to treat conditions and I think
that that will be the case
>> and in fact you know you look at say
anesthesia anesthesia is one of those
things where we're like yeah it's just
anesthesia anesthesia when you start
scratching the surface is so incredibly
strange
>> and they really don't know how it works
right
>> there are many anesthetics people have
no idea how how they work and I mean a
few things right if you look at like
Michael Pollen's new book he talks about
how anesthesia is effective on plants
even though they have
>> obviously completely different nervous
systems slash I should say more anatomy
but it would seem I mean
how should I get into this without
making a mess of things uh there are
some hints of of quantum effects of
anesthesia but putting that aside
>> because I'm not I'm not credible enough
to talk about that at length
>> some of these anesthetics are inert like
they shouldn't do anything.
>> Mhm.
>> Right. So what is happening? And it
would seem that it might be physics and
not chemistry. So it's not it's not
within the realm of chemists say, "Oh,
it's binding to this receptor and doing
A, B, or C." Even though they might
observe effects that mimic those things
>> that it's somehow affecting
bioelectrical fields.
>> And that's the limit of the extent of my
cursory understanding. But it's just
fascinating. There's so many things like
this that we take for granted that we
think are understood by the quote
unquote experts
>> and we have no idea what the mechanism
of action is. There are many examples
like that.
>> But isn't that crazy? Like it's
something we just like take for granted.
We're like, "Yeah, let's pop two of
those." Like we have no idea how it
works. Like what the [ __ ]
>> There there are a lot of those, right?
Like I think for a while that was true
of medafanil. There are many many many
drugs.
>> Oh, do you takeilafilophilaf
whatever that is? Yeah. Boner pills.
>> Do you take it?
>> Uh, no I don't. You don't?
>> I don't because I know there's supposed
to be maybe plausible cognitive benefits
and so on.
>> I get
>> low dose. I just do a little halfer.
>> Yeah. I get and this is not actually
that uncommon. I get horrible
>> flushing
>> back pain.
>> Oh, back pain. Weird.
>> Yeah. It's not super common, but in like
a a percentage of people it's reported
in the literatur. How about with the
other horrible back pain?
>> What about the other ones?
>> Viagra. Viagra similar back pain.
>> Wow.
>> Yeah.
>> What's the deal? Do the people know why
the back pain? They don't know.
>> Oh, they they they do. Yeah. I mean,
they're like there are different types
of phosphodiest phosphodieststerase PTE
inhibitors. I think I'm getting this
right. I'm going to have to fact check
this before this goes
gets published, but basically I want to
say it's like PTE5 or something like
that. So Hubman was talking about
there's a potential benefit both in on
the cognitive side and also obviously
the blood pressure side as well. So
brings down your blood pressure a little
bit and you don't have to take much of
this stuff. You can just take a little
half
>> little nibs.
>> Yeah.
>> I am just on so many things. I'm trying
to
>> But they work for you. Like even though
it hurts your lower back like you're
like a Superman.
>> Yeah. I mean I'll Yeah, sure. I mean
I'll have a huge boner about looked like
in a UFC fighter round roundhouse kicked
me in the in the kidney. Yeah. Oh, cuz
they they your kidneys like it pops out.
Like your back doesn't pop out, but like
my low back hurts so much that I'm like
I can't like I can't sit. I can't stand.
>> I thought your like back muscles got
hard or something and you have like
bulges on your
>> No, I'm just saying it's like it's hard
to enjoy the boner if if you're like
crippled with low back pain.
>> That's fair. That's fair. It is. I got
to tell for people that have never tried
these like I don't need these.
>> But no, but hold on. Like this is the
random show. We're supposed to be
talking about this stuff.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Sure. When you try them for
the first time, it is the weirdest [ __ ]
>> Well, I mean, look,
>> because you reach down and it's not you.
>> Well, this this
>> because it's like you're like, whoa,
>> this is where you have to be careful
with augmentation, right? Because it's
like,
>> for instance, if your eyes are like
going a little bit and then you wear
glasses and you're just like, "Holy
[ __ ] this is a different world."
>> How do you go back to black and white?
>> Right?
>> You know what I mean? It's like this is
another reason why sure like technically
people might be able to use all of these
peptides and testosterone and GH and all
these things and then just get off
because you have postcycle therapy or
whatever but psychologically
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> people can get so addicted
>> to the results because they are obvious
>> if these things are used correctly. You
know what I mean? So, it's kind of like
similarly with
>> this extends back to the AI
conversation, right? It's like, man, the
siren song, the temptation to use AI for
almost everything is so strong.
>> But I'm working on this new book right
now and it's like I am not using it to
write for me because if I do that, I'm
done.
>> Oh, yeah.
>> It's good. It's too good.
>> Well, there's even
>> I'm using it for version control. If
somebody provides edits, I'm like,
compare this to this and give me a
graphic overview. So I can print it out
and look at it in color. Like it can do
some tremendous things. But if you want
to retain a function, a cognitive
ability, be very careful about what you
outsource cuz well, let me throw this
out there for people that that aren't
aware of it because most people won't
be. In the world of AI, what they do
sometimes is they put these elegant
pieces of code that kind of sit on top
of the AI that makes it turbocharges
kind of the AI to do special things,
right?
>> And they're called harnesses. Mhm.
>> And there is a new harness that came out
recently just for writers.
>> Oh god.
>> And so if if you thought Claude or Chad
View was really good at helping you
write, wait till you throw this harness
on top of it. So there's a company
called Every out there and they had
released a a package for coders called
Compound Engineering. They now have one
uh you can just type in every compound
engineering writer harness and it'll
show you the right one. You just install
it into your chatbt or claude and it
will write the book for you. Like it's
it's going to be insane.
Oh yeah.
>> Yeah. You're done.
>> Yeah. Well, I don't know if I'm done. I
mean, I don't think so because I mean,
you've talked about this online and I
think we've texted a little bit about
it, but it's like what's the moat?
>> Reputation.
>> It is reputation, right? So, so I don't
think I'm dead. I think books are harder
and harder to sell as a viable format of
media. Well, it's funny like back in the
day. So, if when I knew when Tim was
writing these books back in the early
days because I first met you when the I
met you the day your first book came
out, the 4-hour work weekek came out
>> and at the party and then, you know, you
would tell me, "Hey, I'm working on this
book." And you would like
>> you would want to keep everything hush
hush. You wouldn't want to tell anybody
because you were like, "Okay, someone
can frontr run me with this idea with
the ideas that I have in here. If any of
this leaks out, right?" And you were
super guarded. That is more of the
reality these days. I mean, if someone
were to find out the next book you're
writing on got a leaked copy of it, they
can rewrite the entire thing and have it
out in like 48 hours, published and
printed. Yeah. I mean, the defense is
No, I know there's the moat of you.
Yeah.
>> Well, I'm just saying like that is why
if if you are writing about the realm of
ideas, that is going to be a hard game
to play.
>> Yeah.
>> Right. If you are writing about lived
experience like I did X, Y, and Z,
>> right?
>> Then I think you have more
defensibility.
Uh, but you know, I I think I'm not sure
we talked about this, but I've I've just
kind of come down to deciding that I'
i'd rather right now. I'm also half
pregnant with this book is is like 80%
of the way there.
>> Yeah. You've been working on this one
for a long time.
>> Yeah, I have. I mean, it's taken it's in
a way, honestly, I've been waiting for
the technology to catch up.
>> Yeah.
>> So that I could make the point that I
wanted to make, which is, look, guys,
this is not a 1% problem. This is a 99%
problem. And the tools are also
available to 99%. Right? Because I was
like, if I published this 5 years ago,
people would be like, "Oh, Crimea River,
Tim Ferrris has too much inbound,
right?" But now I'm like, "How many?"
I'm like, "Okay, you've got what? You've
got iMessage, WhatsApp,
two email addresses,
>> DMs. Everybody's [ __ ] drowning,
right? Everybody's drowning." But I
couldn't have I couldn't have made that
argument as well six years ago
>> as you know like with robots are so good
at imitating humans. Yeah.
>> Although I I do test
>> my team will test things if I'm like if
this is 100% AI written like it's
automatic
>> X right. I just it's automatic archive.
But coming back to I I would just rather
write a book for 10,000 people than do
short form videos for 10 million who
forget it 10 seconds later, you know.
But I'll give I want to I want to share
one piece of long form for people who
who uh can still digest it, which is
hopefully many of you.
>> There is this is a this is a speech and
I read the transcript. It is
exceptional. It's called personal
renewal. It's by John Gardner. G A R D N
E R I don't I have no idea how I found
this thing. It's delivered to Mckenzian
Company in in November 1990. How did I
find this? I have no idea. But it is
full of gems. You can find an audio
version. Just search personal renewal,
John Garder. That's G A R D N R. And
it's it's really about personal personal
renewal continual learning throughout
life. It's really really good. Uh, but
it does require a little bit of foreplay
to to get to the gems. But here's a
really good one and I'll quoting from
the piece here. Remember I mentioned
earlier the myth that learning is for
young people. I want to give you some
examples. In a piece I wrote for Reader
Digest not long ago, I gave what seemed
to me particularly interesting true
example of renewal. The man in question
was 53 years old. Most of his adult life
had been a losing struggle against debt
and misfortune. In military service, he
received a battlefield injury that
denied him the use of his left arm. And
he was seized and held in captivity for
5 years. Later, he held two government
jobs, succeeding at neither. At 53, he
was in prison, and not for the first
time. There in prison, he decided to
write a book driven by heaven knows what
motive. Boredom, the hope of gain,
emotional release, creative impulse, who
can say. And the book turned out to be
one of the greatest ever written, a book
that has enthralled the world for over
350 years. The prisoner was Cervantes.
The book Don Kiote. What a [ __ ] crazy
story.
>> Holy [ __ ] And there are many examples
like this. So, Personal Renewal by John
Gardner, like just maybe print it out,
single task, get away from
notifications. I've read this one a few
times now and uh I just get something
from it every time.
>> That's amazing. Man makeup.
>> Man makeup. Do you wear makeup?
>> I don't wear makeup.
>> Never.
>> On your TV show?
>> My TV show? You mean like when I was on
actual TV? I Yeah. I mean, look, they've
got makeup people who want to like del
deg gloss my head.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Yeah. They'll use like oil
patches.
>> You don't do any like little touch-ups?
>> I don't. I probably should, but I don't.
Yeah. No. No touch-ups.
>> So, I was on a podcast. I was on a
podcast like a month ago and I I looked
like hell. Like I had just flown into
the city.
>> You're like Aluccino after a bender.
>> No, it was sick. Seriously, I just flown
into the city and I I slept like [ __ ]
for some cuz I was at altitude where I
was at and I went on the screen. I was
like I had like I get like rosacea
sometimes in my cheeks and stuff
>> and I just look like [ __ ] I was like
[ __ ] I need to do something like in
case. So you can bleep that. I need to
do something in case like I I just like
going just bleep
>> the f word.
>> Come on. You had 30 of those the last
episode.
>> So I went in to the store. Okay. I'm
going to say I went to Sephora. I went
to [ __ ] Sephora. I never been in that
[ __ ] before ever in my life. And it was
all ladies and I was just like I went in
there and I didn't want makeup. I was
just like, "Hey, do you have something
for like when your cheeks get extra red,
like rosacea and stuff like that? Like,
is there anything you can get?" And they
>> when I'm putting on my little black
dress and my high heels.
>> Exactly. I was I was decked out to the
nines. Like I get gassed up.
>> This is a horrible name for a product,
but it's Dr. Jart. It has something
called
Seca Pear, which is So, get this. It's
It's green. Okay. And I'm like, why is
it green? It's color when mixed with
red,
>> okay,
>> will even out the tone.
>> It's a complimentary color
>> and it's SPF
>> crisp Christmas neutralizing.
>> Yeah. So, watch this. Like I can do I
don't know. We can't get a zoom here,
but like we So, there's little dots
right here. Now, hold on. Watch the
difference now. Hold on. I don't I need
a mirror or something.
>> Is it a lot?
>> I mean, you
>> Okay, watch. Let me just rub it in.
>> All right. You doing You're doing the
This is like an infomercial. You're
doing this the one side. I love it.
>> Okay. So now if we look now
>> like do you notice how much like less
red it is than the other side? And it's
SPF too.
>> I don't but but it looks very well
moisturized.
>> It is very well moisturized. It's got a
SPF. Anyway, my only point is that
>> seeapair C I C A P A I R soothing color
connecting treatment.
>> The reason why I bring this up is
because I know a lot of people have
rosacea and it's a shitty thing. For me,
it's like spicy foods or something and
like you get like extra red cheeks and
all that. And let me tell the truth. And
I wanted something. This is like matte
so like if you're on camera or whatever
it down like you took a bath in olive
oil, right?
>> I just I just I feel for people that
have problems that they don't know how
to fix. And I was like, "Okay, rosacea.
A lot of people have. I might as well
talk about the show."
>> You look like you have fewer crows feet
than I recall. Have you been doing
vampire?
>> I Yeah, I do vampire facials and I do
one. Vampire facials is PRP.
>> Yeah. PRP where they draw your blood.
>> Still haven't tried it. How often do you
do that?
>> Oh, dude. I do it like twice a year.
>> Twice a year.
>> Yeah. So, they draw your blood. It's the
only reason. I mean, I still have
wrinkles. If I scr scrunch up, you can
still see them on the side, but it's way
better. So, they draw your blood. They
spin it. They take out the platelet rich
plasma. And then they do they rub it on.
Well, first they they micro needle your
face. This is going to sound like a lot,
but like it was like there was a
discount package. They micro needle your
face and then they rub it in. And then I
swear after like two weeks like the
wrinkles just go away. Do you look like
you got in a street fight for a couple
days?
>> Uh you're a little red. Yeah, that's why
you got this stuff. But you're a little
red and it it works wonders. And then
one skin with the peptides is awesome.
And I and again I did I did put a small
angel check into into one skin because
it worked so well for me. But
>> that's it, man. Makeup. I want to
mention two other things that I have
really been en enjoying
finding thoughtprovoking at least. One
is a miniseries. I'm curious if you've
seen it. The it's a four-part miniseries
called The Dark Wizard. Have you seen
this? No.
>> Okay.
>> So, The Dark Wizard, which was first
recommended to me by Andrew Huberman and
then a couple of other folks recommended
it.
>> It's about this
wild, brilliant, but totally tormented
artist and athlete named Dean Potter. So
Dean Potter way back in the day, I'm
going to get the timing wrong, but I
want to say like early 90s, sometime in
the '90s, he was on the cover of Outside
magazine, and this guy's story was so
captivating to me that I kept that issue
of Outside magazine with this black and
white photo of him, like very handsome
looking guy, super athletic, and he
pioneered all these new approaches to
climbing, rock climbing. He also was one
of the main, I would say, proilitizers
of slacklining and then highlining,
which is doing like a slack line over a
canyon. Just the scariest stuff.
>> The big long poles and [ __ ] right?
>> No poles.
>> Just just hands.
>> Yeah. No.
>> And then he ended up wanting to push the
boundaries of free soloing, but the
problem is, as he roughly stated it was,
well, when you're free soloing, you
always have to climb well within your
limits. And he's like, I want to push my
limits. So, he started doing something
called free basing where he was
combining free soling with bass jumping.
>> Yeah, I've heard.
>> And this four-part series is insane and
it's incredibly well produced. All of
this archival footage, drawings and
notes from Dean's personal journals all
woven together.
>> There's a lot of darkness like he
struggled with a lot many inner demons
and depression.
And on the flip side, he was just this
absolute genius on so many different
levels. So, I found it to be a really
really thoughtprovoking watch. I
actually binged I I started one at like
I think each is an hour long or roughly
an hour long and I started one at like
11 p.m. and my lady fell asleep in like
20 minutes. Wasn't really her jam and it
was bedtime anyway. And I stayed I
binged the entire series. I stayed up
until like 3:00 in the morning watching
this stuff. I just couldn't stop
watching it.
>> Oh [ __ ] That's a strong recommendation.
I'm going to check that out.
>> Yeah, it's it it ties into a lot of
current interests and also old demons of
my own. So, uh it was uh
it was it was you know brought up it
brought up a lot for me and many people
have enjoyed it. So, the dark wizard
that was his nickname. And then there's
a book that people might not expect I
would bring up. This is not a new book.
This is a book by Studs Turk. Talk about
a good name.
>> T E R Kl. Studs Turkl. He won the Peeler
Prize at one point, I think, for
working. I might be getting the title
wrong, but the book that I was
introduced to is called Hard Times, an
illustrated oral history of the Great
Depression. And it was introduced to me
by Brit of all things. Uh, great guy
named Ed Cook, who I'm not sure if you
know Ed.
>> I know Ed Cook. Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Total total lunatic.
>> Awesome guy. one of the best and most
famous memory competitors formerly like
world champion of mastery
>> of memory has
>> super good person and he's very good at
coaching people to get incredibly good
at memory competition there was an
entire book written about this called
moonwalking with Einstein
>> and he has a startup called Mindmax
which is a learning app if people want
to check it out
>> but this book hard times an illustrated
oral history of the great depression by
studs Turle contains
many dozens of vignettes and profiles of
people who went through the depression
from the most destitute to the rich who
lost everything to the jingle writers
who actually had the most incredible
explosion of creativity during that
period. And
they're very bite-sized profiles. The
stories are told both in their own words
and in the sort of in words of studs
who's uh trying to convey different
perspectives on everything from these
different vantage points and it is a
page turner. It's so well written
>> and it it fleshes out the depression
into something very real and complex,
right? It's not just like one mom with
her hungry kids sitting on a doorstep
looking
>> for Lauren, right? There's so many
different angles to it.
>> And
I just feel like it's one of the one of
the better and most unique
depictions of history that I've that
I've ever come across.
>> It's awesome. I Is there audible on that
or No,
>> I wouldn't be surprised if there is.
Hard times. It's very, very well
written. And Ed told me, he's like,
"Hard times is good, but if you like
that, working is incredible."
>> Uh, and working, as I understand it, is
kind of like dirty jobs before dirty
jobs with micro, but looking at all
these different professions across the
United States.
>> But Hard Times is the one that that that
I've been been cracking. So, if I have
15 minutes
>> and I'm just killing time waiting for
something, I'll pull it up on my Kindle
and I'll read that because you'll get
through like one or two profiles.
>> So, I've been doing this in the sauna
where I put on an audio book and it's
like my way to kind of like just crank
through something
>> and I did something very similar
speaking of new books and I've been
trying to push myself in new directions
of things I would normally never listen
to like what is something that would
never be on my radar and just give me a
whole new perspective on how what people
are consuming media wise. And so my
friend Britt, she was like, "Hey, like
I've got a recommendation for you.
There's this whole genre of books that
are like big." Apparently women like in
their mid30s into their 40s like love
this genre. Have you heard of fairy
porn?
No. I don't know what fairy porn is. Is
this like the what is it called? The
fourth wing. This is This is called A
Court of Thorn and Roses. Have you heard
of that that book?
>> No.
>> Okay. So, I'm like, "Okay, I'll I'll
I'll buy it, right?" And I downloaded on
Audible.
It's damn good. Like, it's it's Is it
like dime store romance novels with like
sophisticated that? But like, I mean,
>> that's what they all say.
>> I never thought I would be listening to
this [ __ ] And I'm
>> But how many times does the word
throbbing come up
>> so far? Like maybe twice.
>> Manhood.
>> But it's It is times four. It's actually
No, but what's different than like the
old like you know when you go to the
grocery store you see like the the dudes
with like the chiseled abs and
everything
>> is they actually are taking these very
sophisticated kind of like almost like
>> you know it's fantasy. It's like well
written fantasy and then there's a
little bit of like like thrown in there
that like everyone's like woo like like
he like did that like you know and so I
would never listen to this [ __ ] ever.
Yeah,
>> but I will say it's interesting cuz they
had like I was selling like 30,000
fivestar reviews. I'm like, how is this
a genre I've just never heard of?
>> So, I'm trying to force myself to say,
okay, you know, once or twice a year,
pick a genre that's just completely
different than you would ever expose
yourself to and go deep. I don't know if
you you've ever done that with any
>> I do this all the time
>> just to find things that I would never
read. Like Hard Times is a good example
where I was just like, Ed, give me a
book that I would never find.
>> Yes. and he was like, "I got one for
you."
>> Uh the So did bring up the fourth wing
because this is one that was everywhere.
I'm sure it had 100,000
>> picture of it.
>> I'm sure it has 100,000 reviews on it's
it's like that.
>> Okay. And basically I saw
again like early to mid maybe like 30 to
40 year old women all over the place
reading this book
>> and they seem to be like business women
and I was like what is going on?
>> Yeah. The person that recommend
>> why are they why are why are they
reading fantasy? Like something doesn't
add up.
>> And then uh not to diminish it. I'm sure
they're great books but it there it's
kind of like dragon porn, right? It's
like there is a porn aspect to the whole
thing.
>> Yeah, there has to be.
>> And what uh some people may not know,
and I think I'm getting this right,
>> it's not like porn. Well, it's not porn.
It's a romance. Uh well, I mean,
>> yeah, there's sex, but porn is very
different. Like, that's not I mean,
look,
>> yeah,
>> depends on what we're talking about, but
yeah,
>> it's not like, right, gang bangs every
five pages, but there's still some
pretty explicit stuff. The what people
may not realize, I am almost 100% sure
I'm getting this right, but I'm not
going to fact check it now on my phone.
Do you know how Fifty Shades of Gray
started?
>> No.
>> It was fanfiction.
It was Twilight series fanfiction. So,
somebody was writing like an extension
of like within the Twilight world, her
own fiction, super sexualized,
>> and that turned into Fifty Shades of
Gray.
>> Wild.
>> Isn't that crazy?
>> That is insane. It is something like
that. It may not be Twilight
specifically, but it was fanfiction,
fantasy that then got converted into its
own franchise for 50 Shades.
>> I couldn't do it. I couldn't do the
writing. I tried and I just all due
respect to the author, it just was not I
could not digest the pros, but
>> what it what it demonstrated to me was
like the power of a simple premise,
right? It's just like you have I mean
look people are probably familiar with
the series but it's like you have this
whatever it is like what's his name
Christian Gray like this like
billionaire rich guy with a sex dungeon
and then like
>> you know
>> and super explicit right and you know I
remember a number of different uh pieces
of coverage described it as mommy porn
you know for what that's worth but
it impressed me I I I tried to get
through the pros. I couldn't do it. But
the power of a simple premise,
>> right? It's like how how visceral and
simple is your premise and concede. And
honestly, that's where, for instance,
>> my third book, the 4-Hour Chef, that's
where it failed. It tried to do too
much. It was like three books in one. It
was not a simple premise. It was very
complicated
>> because I felt like it was wellreceived.
>> It was wellreceived. I mean, it sold
hundred hundreds of thousands of copies.
all sold like 120,000 copies the first
week. But that was a function of my
diehard audience who would take me at my
word that it's worth reading.
>> But if you if you went blind, unfamiliar
with me at all to the say Amazon page,
>> it tried to do too much.
>> And I think this is true with
presentations. Like if I'm talking to
someone who's going, for instance, I was
just coaching someone who's going on 60
minutes, right? And they wanted to talk
about messaging.
>> Mhm.
>> And or if I'm talking to somebody who's
got a TED talk coming up and they're
they're asking for advice. You know, my
advice is is always the same. I didn't
come up with this. Somebody else gave it
to me, which is like presentations fail
from too much information, not too
little information.
>> And I think that's true with books, too.
It's like does this conjure a simple
image in someone's head like immediately
and that is not
>> easy to do while being differentiated
right so 50 shades of gray nailed it
>> completely nailed it and that has turned
this thing into a global phenomenon
right
>> whereas this third book which I'm still
very proud of I think it's a great book
but it it's really three or four books
combined into one
>> and to try to convey that to anyone in a
paragraph is next to impossible Yeah, I
mean the same applies to so much in life
though. I mean even on the product side
of all the products that I've built over
the years, it is, you know, and I watch
entrepreneurs going to launch new
consumer products or whatever it may be.
The ones that boil the ocean and throw
in every single feature and they're
like, "Oh, but wouldn't it be great if
it had this?" And I'm like, "Yeah, maybe
someday." Yeah.
>> But can you really distill down this
idea to that one concept so that when
you're in that I used to call it the
crowded bar conversation? not the
elevator pitch, but the crowded bar in
what does
>> it to where they say, "Oh yeah, I'll go
check that out." You know, and often
times you can't do it. So the battle is
cutting features out. This is what Steve
Jobs was so good at.
>> It's like he could have added App Store
on day one for the iPhone, but it was
like he didn't he was like it's going to
do these 10 things really well and then
slowly build on on that base, you know?
>> Yeah. I mean, if if the V1 iPhone could
get away with no copy paste, remember
that?
>> Oh, yeah. That's right.
>> Suck, bro. Talk about minimalist.
>> Yeah. So true.
>> And
this is also part of the reason why,
frankly, the the book that I'm working
on right now is has taken so long. So,
I'm like, it's not ready just yet.
Because the way that I try to explain it
in like the crowded bar test, there are
ways I could probably do market analysis
to get more comfortable or to confirm or
disisconfirm this concern maybe. But if
I talk to say some of our friends who
are super busy, right? And I tell them
it's a book on saying no.
>> Mhm.
>> And focusing in a world of noise, right?
How do you create systems for that?
They're like, "Fuck, I need that right
now. Please send send me the draft
today. I don't care if it's right,
>> but for nine out of 10 people who are
not like one of our friends or one of
the podcast guests who've been on, when
I tell them that, I do not see like the
slight eye opening and lean in. I don't
see it. They're like, "Oh, interesting."
And I'm like, "Hm." Is it because most
people are looking for more things to
say yes to because they don't have the
opportunity?
>> Well, this is what I'm working on
deducing. Like, is it the title? Maybe
it's the title, right? So, I was just
playing around with that yesterday.
>> Is it the
>> description where the promise is
unclear?
>> Is it the fact that it sounds perhaps
negative instead of affirming?
>> Right? Saying no versus something else
because a third of the book actually is
like how to pick the one or two things
that change everything to say yes to,
>> right? So, it's like, hm, maybe the book
positioning should be more focused on
that.
>> Mhm.
>> It would require a very heavy lift on
like revamping a bunch of the
positioning in the book or explanatory
stuff in the book. Uh, but I am
trying to learn from past mistakes,
right? I don't think this book tries to
do too much. I don't think that's a
problem. And everybody who actually
reads it or test read it, they're like,
I was never bored. Like, I would gift
this book to my friends more than any of
your other books. So, it's like it's
working,
>> but
>> if people go to the Amazon page and the
title and the description don't work, it
doesn't matter. You're dead.
>> Right.
>> So, that like 50 Shades of Gray genius,
>> I want to get that right. Which is part
of the reason why I'm like, I don't need
to publish a book. I didn't take an
advance, right? Which I mean, it has its
own drawbacks. I don't have a gun to the
head. I don't have accountability to a
publisher, which is actually can be a
bad thing
>> because like we have 20 different things
we're doing at any given time. It's very
easy to be like, "Yeah, I'll just push
it off another six months. It's fine."
And that's actually not a great thing
when it comes to writing books. So, TBD,
but that'll get figured out. I feel
pretty confident in that. You know, that
my aim is to have the book done in the
next eight weeks.
>> Oh, wow.
>> Yeah.
>> And so, when you go from that to no
publisher, like how do you think about
printing? How do you think about
distribution? Are you going to do like
author's equity or any other
>> I'm leaning I'm leaning towards author's
equity.
I'm a small investor in that company. I
mean, not enough to
>> People should know that's James Claire's
like from James, one of the largest
investors. I mean, talk about a
phenomenon, man. Holy [ __ ]
>> What is it? 25, 30 million copies sold.
Nobody does that in prescriptive
non-fiction. Nobody does that. I mean,
James is a nonrecurring phenomenon. Very
nice guy, very smart guy. Uh, and he's
he's one of the largest investors in
Author's Equity. Uh, great team at
Author's Equity. So, I'm leaning towards
doing something with them. I don't know
what the exact form will take, right? Do
I do all formats? Do I do some formats?
>> I'm not overly worried about that. I was
just chatting with them the other day
just to figure out like what are the
actual lead times if we're going to do
the Dead Tree format in addition to
other things. I thought about only doing
Kindle and Audible, but I feel like this
book
>> here's a hot take.
>> Feels like a giftable book. Well, it's a
giftable book. But here's the other hot
take is like the more
>> this become I'm holding up my iPhone.
The more these become a digital leash
>> that is feeding you 24/7 distraction,
the more I want to have a format that
forces people to single task. And the
only option for that right now, I
suppose you could do it on a Kindle if
people are using an actual Kindle device
>> that is not internet connected for
distraction, but print is a great way to
single task.
>> No, I know.
>> And this is also this is a workbook.
This is not a passive spectator book.
Like if you put in the work like if you
put four hours of work into this book,
it should save you four.
>> Yeah. If you put four, let's call it
five. If you put five hours of work,
inflation, if you put five hours of work
into this book, it's like it should save
you a 100red hours in the next year if
you're a busy person,
>> like without question
>> and it it just goes up from there. So,
>> so we'll see. But the goal is to be done
in the next 8 weeks.
>> What is the lead time just out of
curiosity for someone looking to make a
actual physical book? Like is it 3
months, 5 months? Like
>> it depends a lot on who you're talking
to. Some publishers
>> how big the first run is, right?
>> Yeah. And well, yeah, the the size
doesn't matter as much as you might
think. If it's a simple page layout,
black and white or twocolor,
>> I would say it's still pretty slow,
right? But there's a lot that goes into
it, right? Like if you're going to get a
polished book and you're not just
self-pubbing whatever comes off your
laptop, if you're going to have copy
editors and professional layout and so
on, like there are things that make that
easier. I'm sure AI could do a lot of
page layout at this point. I'm sure
people are developing harnesses that'll
help with that specifically,
>> but if if you're looking to have and I'm
not sure how relevant this is to me at
this point, honestly, in terms of like
retail distribution, I don't know how
much it matters in terms of market share
at this point. Things are changing so
quickly and have been changing so
quickly. But if you really want like the
full traditional experience, I would say
from what you consider finished book,
but there's still people who are going
to do copy editing and everything else,
probably a year.
>> Wow.
>> Yeah. Maybe more.
>> That's slow.
>> Now, there are cases where you can do a
crash book where it's like, okay, let's
just say,
>> I mean, this is maybe not a lovely
example, but it's like Princess Diana
dies. Publisher wants to be first out of
the gate. Can they get a book printed
and out the door in 3 months? Yeah, they
can if they make it the top priority and
everything else goes to the back of the
line.
>> Mhm.
>> Yeah. If in most cases if their primary
distribution is in the US and they have
printers in the US, a lot of publishers
uh print overseas.
Uh so those are all factors that go into
it. And like part of me is like man once
I'm done with this I want to out ASAP. I
don't want to like wait for a year. So
like what does that mean? Do I not do
print? Right.
>> Right. Do I do some small print run? It
might be interesting to just do one
print run ever. Yeah. Do I do I do
publish on demand? Right. Like that you
can get out the door quickly with with
with POD and the quality has gone up a
lot. But the collectibility of a single
run of like 10,000 could be really
interesting.
>> I mean, yeah, I could do that. I mean,
who knows? Maybe I do that and then I'm
like, hey, if you want the book, like
you can either get a hard copy now and
there are 10,000 copies,
>> right? Or you can get it in a year or
you can get a different format. Yeah.
Right. I mean
>> that's cool.
>> So I get I get excited about it.
It's a strong book. Like I I feel very
very good about it. I wouldn't I mean I
wouldn't put it out otherwise. I cut it
from I think it was 870 pages down to
like 350. That is a lot of cutting. Holy
[ __ ] That's a lot of cutting. Yeah.
>> So everything that is in the book right
now has been rated by
proof like test readers and proof
readers multiple test readers as an
eight ner 8 n or 10 out of 10 in
quality. Like everything that remains is
kind of cream of the crop. So
>> that's awesome.
>> Yeah. Should be strong.
>> Excited to check it out.
>> Yeah. We'll see. Anything else we should
talk about? No, I think I'm good. I
think I covered everything I wanted to
cover. You know, I'll send out some of
those invites. I can get more of those
instinct invites. keenrose.com
newsletter over there. Sign up and I
will send a bunch out when this goes
live.
>> Sweet. And then just uh just to add to
the dueling email newsletters.
>> You already mentioned yours earlier,
[ __ ]
>> I know. I'm going to do tim.blog Friday.
I don't even know if I'm pointing at the
right camera.
>> No, it's your newsletter is great.
>> Five five bullet Friday.
>> Yeah, there's five bullets. The kevin
rose.com newsletter is slightly longer,
a little bit more information dense.
Probably more takeaways there. So just
chemrosse.com also includes a
>> includes a free nude.
>> Yeah, I include one foot picture with
every new subscriber.
>> Please join my only fans.
>> I I'm going to make one more
recommendation which is I'm not going to
say anti- AI but it's a nice
counterbalance. I don't know if he wants
credit, so I'm not going to mention our
friend who sent this to us, but there is
a short article called Please Use AI by
someone called Sean Smucker. Smu C.
Please use AI. And
it's a beautiful piece about preserving
the beauty and integrity of human
interaction, right? And why
you should not always strive for
optimizing efficiency with LLMs and
computers. So check it out. Please use
AI by Sean. It's S A WN Smucker. It's
really, really good. I've been sending
that to
to different uh different friends of
mine. And uh what I put that because I
put it in the newsletter um not too long
ago, maybe two months ago, and I I
mentioned that the please use AI piece
reminds me of a Kurt Vonagget, one of my
favorite writers passage that is about
telling his wife he's going out to buy
an envelope. So this is this is Kurt
Vonagget, wrote Breakfast of Champions
and tons of other classics. So, this is
Kurt. She says, "Well, you're not a poor
man, you know. Why don't you go online
and buy a 100 envelopes and put them in
the closet?" And so, I pretend not to
hear her and go out to get an envelope
because I'm going to have a hell of a
good time in the process of buying one
envelope. I'm going to meet a lot of
people and see some great looking babes
and a fire engine goes by and I give
them the thumbs up and ask a woman what
kind of dog that is. And I don't know.
The moral of the story is we're here on
Earth to fart around and don't let
anybody tell you different. And of
course, the computers will do us out of
that. What the computer doesn't realize,
what what the computer people don't
realize or they don't care is we're
dancing animals.
So check out Please Use AI by Sean
Smucker. It's a good one. I'm actually
very very very bullish on this idea that
AI will make almost everything that we
need to do in terms of the tactical
day-to-day stuff kind of just almost
handled to the extent to where we can
get together in person in real life,
hang out, hopefully have more leisure
time. Yeah.
>> To and I think there will like with
everything I mean we've seen we've seen
this with alcohol in the last decade.
Like alcohol consumption is like at all
time low right now, right? There's a
there's always a pendulum that swings
back the other way.
>> Yeah. The ketamine going the other
direction.
>> No, no doubt. But like my we see this
like social media like oh now it's bad
for us less people are wanting less of
that. Like here's here's something I
didn't think of. Could the decline in
alcohol consumption actually be
reflective of people sitting at home and
not socializing outside?
>> I know. I love alcohol.
>> Do you know what I mean though?
>> I have no idea.
>> But but you know what I'm talking about,
right? like it it could actually
correlate to people
>> spending more time at home on their
computers and their phones.
>> Yeah.
>> Uh what I would say is with with the AI
stuff, right? I mean, it's
>> I hope it results in people having more
inerson interactions. I do think that
people are going to feel the poison,
right? Like the dose makes the poison. I
think they'll feel that it's not good
for them in a in a in a very visceral,
>> deep way that has not perhaps been as
obvious in the last 5 years minus AI.
But, and I'm not the first person to
observe this, it's like if interacting
with a digital companion is easier than
interacting with your actual partner, if
they're always supportive and saying the
right things and they're not getting
disregulated and freaking out like all
humans do,
>> right? If kids find their customized LLM
a better parent
>> easier to deal with because it
eliminates some of the messiness,
>> right,
>> of unpredictable human interactions.
You know, what are the consequences of
that? The leisure time, I hope that's
true. I have not ever there have been so
many technologies with that promise. The
industrial revolution, we can go through
a long list and
I have not yet seen it, right? Like I
don't know anyone who's like, I used AI
to free up a bunch of free time that I'm
now using for kiteboarding and knitting.
They're like, I was doing two projects,
but now I can do 10 projects or
something always fills the gap, right?
Something's always going to fill the gap
and you have to be very selective about
what's going to fill that gap. But I
will say for me, the daily grind of
email and a lot of those other things
now that I have these and it's going to
be like, "Hey, Kevin, you need to pay
attention to this." I don't have to
check all the other spam and all the
other crap that's coming in there. It
has freed up time.
>> Now, am I using it to AI code then? Yes,
I am. I'm going right back in. But in
theory, I could be doing woodworking or
some other thing.
>> The woodworking
comes up every nine months.
>> You know, Japanese joinery is amazing.
>> I know your Japanese woodworking is like
my JeanClaude Vanam splits. I'm like,
you know, someday.
>> Yeah, exactly.
>> I'm going to get there.
>> Oh, no doubt.
>> Someday. between two chairs. I'm going
to do it in splits. It's like, yeah,
we'll see with those hips.
>> Do you not getting any?
>> Do you have a competition
>> for which one?
>> You can do the splits
>> first.
>> I thought it was going to be if you can
get to Japanese woodworking before I
>> I'm down to I want to I've been going to
Stretch Lab. I've been having people
stretch me out. I'll be able to do the
splits and then Vanam split within 6
months.
>> Within six months.
>> Oh, 100%.
>> How much you want to bet?
>> I'll put some Zcash on that. How much
you
>> You want to do $500 of charity?
>> Okay. So if my choice
>> Well, hold on. First of all, this is
just a bet about whether Kevin does
something in six months.
>> The splits.
>> Yeah. Yeah. So I'm I'm out of the
picture.
>> Why are you out of the picture?
>> Well,
I'm just saying you you're
>> Oh, you don't want to do the splits?
>> I don't care that much about it for
>> But if you're saying you're going to get
to Sean Glenn Vanam splits in 6 months,
I'm like, I will take the other side of
that bet.
>> Okay.
>> 500 bucks to charity.
>> To charity. Charity of your choice or
mine. So either brain stem or zen
meditation is where it's going.
>> Okay. Yeah. Something apolitical, not
[ __ ] So you're just for clarity,
you're saying you're going to be able to
do JeanClaude Van Dams between two
chairs in 6 months.
>> Okay. So just as a reminder, just so I I
have this correct
>> one leg on one chair, the other on the
other chair, hovering in the air.
>> Yeah.
>> Do I have to be like full straight line?
Like
>> I mean you can have like
>> like an inch and a half.
>> Sure. Inch and a half. Okay. You're
gonna do that.
>> But do I have to pull myself up? Like is
that hard to do? I don't know.
>> Yeah, you have to be stupidly strong and
you're like adductors. Otherwise, it
just tears your legs out like like
chicken legs. Yeah.
>> We're going to do this live on the
podcast and I'm going to rip my groin
and I'll be in a wheelchair for 6 months
for 500 bucks.
>> Yeah, sure.
>> On that note, folks, another random
show. Kev, Kev, great to see you.
>> Yeah.
>> And we'll put stuff in the show notes.
God knows. Sorry to my post-production
team for
>> lots of supplements,
>> for all the things you're gonna need to
put in, but tim.blogpodcast for people
who want to check it out and tim.com.
>> Great newsletter.
>> There you go. All right. Thanks for
tuning in, guys. See you.
>> See you.